Dawit Mureja Argaw

Ph.D. Candidate, EE, KAIST

Research Interests

My research interests lie in the general areas of computer vision and deep learning with a particular focus on video-related topics including video restoration, video synthesis, video editing, long-form and multimodal video understanding, video summarization and video generation but not limited to.

Webpage: https://dawitmureja.github.io

Email: dawitmureja@kaist.ac.kr

EDUCATION

• KAIST
Integrated M.S./Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering

Daejeon, South Korea
Sep 2018 - Sep 2024 (expected)

KAISTB.S. in Electrical Engineering; GPA: 3.9/4.3 (Magna Cum Laude)

Sep 2014 - Jul 2018

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

NVIDIA Research Santa Clara, CA Research Intern, Deep Imagination Research Group Nov 2023 - Present Adobe Research San Jose, CA Research Intern, Natural Language Group May 2023 - Sep 2023 **KAUST** Saudi Arabia (Remote) Research Intern, Image and Video Understanding (IVUL) Lab Nov 2022 - May 2023 Adobe Research San Jose, CA (Remote) Research Intern, Deep Learning Group Aug 2021 - Nov 2021 KAIST Daejeon, South Korea Research Assistant, Robotics and Computer Vision (RCV) Lab Sep 2018 - Sep 2023 Daejeon, South Korea Research Assistant, Multimodal AI (MMAI) Lab Sep 2023 - Present

Publications

- Scaling Up Video Summarization Pretraining with Large Language Models. CVPR, 2024.
 Dawit Mureja Argaw, Seunghyun Yoon, Fabian Caba Heilbron, Hanieh Deilamsalehy, Trung Bui, Zhaowen Wang, Franck Dernoncourt, Joon Son Chung.
- Towards Automated Movie Trailer Generation. CVPR, 2024.
 Dawit Mureja Argaw, Mattia Soldan, Alejandro Pardo, Chen Zhao, Fabian Caba Heilbron, In So Kweon, Bernard Ghanem.
- Long-range Multimodal Pretraining for Movie Understanding. ICCV, 2023.
 Dawit Mureja Argaw, Fabian Caba Heilbron, Joon-Young Lee, Markus Woodson, In So Kweon.
- The Anatomy of Video Editing: A Dataset and Benchmark Suite for AI-Assisted Video Editing. ECCV, 2022. Dawit Mureja Argaw, Fabian Caba Heilbron, Joon-Young Lee, Markus Woodson, In So Kweon.
- Long-term Video Frame Interpolation via Feature Propagation. CVPR, 2022. Dawit Mureja Argaw, In So Kweon.
- Motion-blurred Video Interpolation and Extrapolation. AAAI, 2021. Dawit Mureja Argaw, Junsik Kim, Francois Rameau, In So Kweon.
- Optical Flow Estimation from a Single Motion-blurred Image. AAAI, 2021.
 Dawit Mureja Argaw, Junsik Kim, Francois Rameau, Jae Won Cho, In So Kweon.
- Blurry Video Compression: A Trade-off between Visual Enhancement and Data Compression. WACV, 2024. Dawit Mureja Argaw, Junsik Kim, In So Kweon.
- Restoration of Video Frames from a Single Blurred Image with Motion Understanding. CVPR-W (Oral), 2021. Dawit Mureja Argaw, Junsik Kim, Francois Rameau, Chaoning Zhang, In So Kweon.

- Empirical study on using Adapters for debiased Visual Question Answering. CVIU, 2023. Jae Won Cho, Dawit Mureja Argaw, Yeongtaek Oh, Dong-Jin Kim, In So Kweon.
- LEMMS: Label Estimation of Multi-feature Movie Segments. ICCV-W, 2023. Bartolomeo Vacchetti, Dawit Mureja Argaw, Tania Cequtelli.
- ResNet or DenseNet: Introducing Shortcuts to ResNet. WACV, 2021. Chaoning Zhang*, Philipp Benz*, Dawit Mureja Argaw, Seokju Lee, Junsik Kim, Francois Rameau, Jean Charles Bazin, In So Kweon.
- DeePTZ: Deep Self-Calibration for PTZ cameras. WACV, 2020. Chaoning Zhang, Francois Rameau, Junsik Kim, Dawit Mureja Argaw, Jean Charles Bazin, In So Kweon.
- Revisiting Residual Networks with Nonlinear Shortcuts. BMVC (Spotlight), 2019.
 Chaoning Zhang, Francois Rameau, Seokju Lee, Junsik Kim, Philipp Benz, Dawit Mureja Argaw, Jean Charles Bazin, In So Kweon.
- Automatic spine segmentation from CT images using convolutional neural network via redundant generation of class labels. JCDE, 2019.
 Malinda Vania*, Dawit Mureja Argaw*, Deukhee Lee (*equal contribution).

HONORS AND AWARDS

HONORS AND AWARDS	
Top Reviewer Award Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)	2023
Outstanding Reviewer Award CVEU Workshop at ICCV	2023
• Outstanding Reviewer Award International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)	2023
• Best Poster Award What is Motion For? (WiMF) Workshop at ECCV	2022
Outstanding Reviewer Award European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)	2022
Finalist Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship Korea	2023
Magna Cum Laude KAIST Electrical Engineering Department	2018
• Excellent Research Award KAIST Undergraduate Research Participation (URP)	2017
• Dean's List KAIST School of Freshman	2015
• KAIST Scholarship Full scholarship for B.S., and Integrated M.S./Ph.D. programs	2014-Present

ACADEMIC SERVICES

- Reviewer: ICML, ICLR, NeurIPS, CVPR, ICCV, ECCV, BMVC, WACV, TPAMI, ICRA
- Student Volunteer: ICLR 2020, ICML 2020, NeurIPS 2020